Sheet music collection on medical themes
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Miscellaneous, 6.
  - Other medical music
    - Medical Students Songbook
      Edited by A. L. Nicholson. Melbourne: Medical Students Society, University of Melbourne, 1955. The book contains words of songs only. Some of the songs are medical, and others are popular songs.
    - Excerpts from A Collection of New, Standard and Popular Humorous Songs.
      "Selected and edited with New Symphonies & Accompaniments, by J. L. Hatton." London: Boosey & Co., 1890s. The medical songs have been selected by a past owner from the book. They are Mary's Ghost (The Anatomy Song), When a Man's a Little Bit Poorly, Oh! My Tooth It Aches, and Doctor Brown.
  - Music publishers taking patent medicine advertisements
    In this miscellaneous group, a music publisher sells sheet music that is partly funded by patent medicine advertisements.
    - Pine Mountain Merrymakers (M. M. Cole Publishing Co.), 1935
      This book of songs was copyrighted in 1935 by the M. M. Cole Publishing Co., Chicago. On the back cover is a full page advertisement for Pinex Cough Syrup, prepared by the Pinex Co., Fort Wayne, Indiana.
    - Blue Grass Roy (M. M. Cole Publishing Co.), 1935
      This book of songs was copyrighted in 1935 by the M. M. Cole Publishing Co., Chicago. On the back cover is a full page advertisement for Hamlin's Wizard Oil, which is said to "relieve muscular aches and pains."
    - The Maid Who Lives Over the Way (Paladin Publishing Co.), ca. 1880
      The Paladin Publishing Company, Philadelphia, planned to publish a new piece of music each month to be sold for no more than three cents a copy. The inside cover contains a full-page advertisement for Mackie's Sure Dyspepsia Cure, prepared by A. J. H. Mackie, Philadelphia.
    - Our Musical Guest (Bailey, White & Co.), 1873
      Two songs published in volume 1 of the periodical or series, Our Musical Guest, published by Bailey, White, & Co., Boston. The song sheets, dated June 1873 and Spring 1874, include advertisements for various medical and other products.
    - Song sheets from an unidentified journal, 19th cent.
      The songs are from an unidentified 19th century publication. With the music are advertisements including those for Mann's Health-Lift, Brooklyn, N.Y., "a thorough Curative System for Ladies and Gentlemen, in ten minutes once a day."